A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, New York City Decentralization of Schools FA1524
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence Files of William H. Nims, 1967-1968; 2; 1.41 Cubic Feet 3 legal document boxes
  - William H. Nims - Samples, Mimeographed Letters Addressed to Semon E. Knudsen, 1968 October 23-28 (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - No Name/No Address - Ford Motor Company/W. H. Nims, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - A-F, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 177-182)
  - G-R, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 183-194)
  - S-Z, 1967-1968 (Box 19, Folder 195-201)
- Clippings, 1968-1973; 3; 0.94 Cubic Feet 2 legal document boxes
  This series contains newspaper clippings related to school decentralization in New York City, including conflicts over Intermediate School 201 in East Harlem (many clippings related to the controversial Malcolm X memorial speech delivered at the school by Herman B. Ferguson, profiles of David Spencer, chairman of the I.S. 201 governing board, and profiles of Rhody McCoy, Ocean Hill-Brownsville unit administrator), the Mayor's Advisory Panel on Decentralization plan, the Board of Education's counterplan for decentralization, passage of the decentralization bill, decentralization of other schools across the country, and the state of education in New York City.
  A note found in the original box indicates that the clippings were sent to Richard Magat by Charles Wilson, the I.S. 201 unit administrator.
  - Clippings - Decentralization, I.S. 201 and David Spencer, 1968-1971 (Box 19, Folder 202-203)
    In addition to clippings, includes a 'Brief Summary of the I.S. 201 Story,' I.S. 201 School Demonstration Project: A Proposal Submitted to the New York City Board of Education for a Decentralized School District in 1968, and Community Control vs. Decentralization, C. E. Wilson - Brief Talk by Unit Administrator of I.S. 201 Complex -- To Commission of Human Rights sponsored meeting June 28, 1968
  - Clippings - Passage of Decentralization Bill, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 204)
  - Clippings, 1969-1972 (Box 20, Folder 205-207)
  - Clippings - Ocean Hill-Brownsville School Board, 1969-1973 (Box 20, Folder 208)